<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on CFE.dev</title>
    <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on CFE.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cfe.dev/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/webdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/webdev/</guid>
      <description>New technologies and methods are empowering web developers to build more advanced user experiences (UX). These rich experiences are often the competitive edge a product or service needs to take off. Web developers must balance the desire for engaging user interfaces with accessibility, while reaching a wide audience across browsers and devices. They must have an excellent understanding of HTML/CSS, JavaScript, frameworks, performance, web standards, design, and so much more. Our sessions cover the latests tips and tricks for making it all work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/javascript/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript has taken over the software development world and established the web as an application platform. This popular language powers real-time web sites, mobile apps, games, and lightning fast services. JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s growth has made it difficult to keep track of all it can do. New frameworks, libraries, and tools are released all the time.
New developers may find themselves wrestling with questions like React vs Vue, whether or not to invest into TypeScript, or how to tie different tools together to deliver a blissful JavaScript-centric product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/web-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/web-development/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevOps</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/devops/</guid>
      <description>Architecting your application to support surges of traffic used to be a costly dark art. Serverless, AWS, Kubernetes, and newer technologies have made building, managing, and scaling high performance applications achievable. Our sessions cover many of these techniques and shed light on what it takes to make it through launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Stuff</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/stuff/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the best way to learn is to tackle a fun challenge, try something a bit out of the ordinary, or take a fresh perspective to an old problem. Our speakers have done just that, from building robots to deep-diving virtual reality. These sessions are a great way to generate new ideas for your next project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career &amp; Culture</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/culture/</guid>
      <description>Soft skills are rarely the focus of bootcamps or coursework and are more often acquired through years of experience. Learning to lead, empathize with others, and navigate difficult situations are key to the career progression of any developer. Building these skills can help you craft an environment that you and others enjoy. But you don’t have to do it the hard way! Learn from the speakers in these sessions and take the next step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/categories/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/categories/software/</guid>
      <description>The sessions listed here will introduce you to languages, tools, or ideas you can use to level up. Many of these sessions touch on core concepts essential to modern development, such as scalable architecture and managing projects with Git. With such a range of topics, there’s something for developers of all levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>