<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtual Meetups and Sessions for Technologists on CFE.dev</title>
    <link>https://cfe.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtual Meetups and Sessions for Technologists on CFE.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cfe.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Meetups</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Meetups We add new virtual meetups, online trainings, and other events all the time. Subscribe to our mailing list to be notified about everything we have&amp;nbsp;planning.   There are no upcoming virtual meetups scheduled. Check back soon!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sessions</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/</guid>
      <description>Discover Sessions We have a huge and evergrowing library of session from the top experts in development and technology across a wide range of topics.      Career &amp;amp; Culture  Learn to lead with empathy and master soft skills.      DevOps  Launch &amp;amp; scale high performance apps like a pro.      JavaScript  React, Vue, JAMSTACK, and everything in-between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe to our Mailing List</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/subscribe/</guid>
      <description> Subscribe to the Mailing List We are constantly adding new live, virtual meetups and new recorded sessions. Stay up to date with the latest content as well as trends and news in the technology space by joining our mailing list.   tag --   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speakers</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/</guid>
      <description>Speakers We&#39;ve been fortunate to welcome an amazing list of technology and development experts as speakers - both online or in-person. This isn&#39;t just a boast - check this list out!
      Aimee Knight Software Engineer at Tuft &amp;amp; Needle                  Alison Falk CEO of WIT PGH               Alyssa Nicoll Developer Advocate at Progress                  Amanda Loftis UX Director at Fluree               Andrea Griffiths Community Specialist at GitHub               Andy Barnov Teacher at Le Wagon Berlin               Ayan George Organizer of Orlando Go               Ayşegül Yönet Senior Azure Cloud Developer Advocate at Microsoft               Ben Ilegbodu Principal Frontend Engineer at Stitch Fix                  Bianca Gandolfo Software Engineer at Thumbtack                  Brad Marsh Senior Developer at SmartThings            Brandon Satrom Developer Evangelist at Particle                  Brian Leroux Co-founder at Begin                  Burke Holland Principal Developer Advocate at Microsoft                  Carlos Souza Author at Pluralsight                  Chris Coyier Founder at CSS Tricks                  Christina Aldan Speaker, Trainer, Consultant               David Khourshid Software Engineer at Microsoft                  Diana Rodriguez Developer Advocate at Nexmo                  Divya Tagtachian Developer Advocate at Progress                  Em Lazer-Walker Cloud Developer Advocate at Microsoft                  Estelle Weyl Developer, Author, Trainer                  Gift Egwuenu Developer Evangelist at Datopian                  Helena McCabe Senior Front-end Developer at Lullabot               Henri Helvetica Freelance Developer            Holly Schinsky Software Engineer at Adobe                  James Thomas Developer Advocate at IBM Cloud                  Jay Hoffmann Lead Developer at Reaktiv Studios                  Jem Young Software Engineer at Netflix                  Jen Looper Cloud Developer Advocate Lead at Microsoft                  Jenell Pizarro User Experience Consultant at Capco               Jeremy Likness Product Manager at Microsoft                  Jo Franchetti Developer Advocate at Ably Realtime                  Johnny Boursiquot Site Reliability Engineer at Heroku                  Jory Burson Open Source Educator at Bocoup                  Kent C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/conduct/</guid>
      <description>Contact Us This code of conduct applies to any online and in-person events. If you encounter any violations, please contact brian@certifiedfreshevents.com.
 All attendees, speakers, sponsors and volunteers at our virtual meetups, live events or other organized activity, whether online or in-person, are required to agree with the following code of conduct. The organizers will enforce this code throughout the event. We expect cooperation from all participants to help ensure a safe environment for everybody.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Native Mobile Development Changed the Way I Write Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/native-to-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/native-to-web/</guid>
      <description>Web developers tend to be unabashed defenders of the web platform, and tend to view native mobile platforms as proprietary, gated and bloated.
As a long-time web developer I felt this way too, but then something unexpected happened: I joined the dark side, and spent five years of my career working on—gasp—iOS and Android applications.
Now, like an explorer returning from a multi-year safari—I have so much to share! In this talk I’ll discuss how native development has improved the way I write code for the web, and how you can incorporate the best native app performance and testing tips into your web workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving from Native Mobile to Web Development</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/native-to-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/native-to-web/</guid>
      <description>Getting out of our comfort zones can be scary but often leads to new realizations and inspirations. In this session, TJ VanToll explains the things he learned when he returned to web development after spending years deep in mobile app development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join CFE.dev</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/join/</guid>
      <description>Join &amp;amp; Get FULL Access  Your Name  Email Address  Password Pick a good one!   Sign Up Cancel  Have an account already? Log in instead.
 Why Join CFE.dev?     Catch meetups live Learn alongside the community in real-time.      New content regularly 2-3 meetups a month provides plenty to learn.      Stay up on the latest tech Stay fresh by learning new things from industry experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log in to CFE.dev</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/login/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/login/</guid>
      <description>Log In &amp;amp;Get Watching  Email Address  Password  Log In Cancel  Need an account? Join CFE.dev instead.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Web Applications with Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/vue-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/vue-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Vue.js has continued to gain popularity in the web development community in part because it has a gentler learning curve than other frameworks, a good developer experience and offers good performance and size efficiency without giving up on functionality. In this live, hands-on workshop, Raymond Camden will give you everything you need to get started with Vue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Web Applications with Vue.js</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/vue-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/vue-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This is an introductory course to the Vue.js progressive web framework. In this course, we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce Vue.js and give multiple real world examples that can be used in real web sites. We&amp;rsquo;ll also give folks the why of Vue.js so you can better make the decision of when and where, or even if, to use Vue.js.
Workshop Outline  Introduction - Course prerequisites and why I use Vue Using Vue - Focused on core syntax Exercises - Form validation and search Working with Components Exercise - Building an image placeholder component Working with the Vue CLI and Creating Vue Applications Exercise - Creating a simple Vue app Using Vue Routing Exercise - Building a multi-page Vue app State Management with Vuex Exercise - Using Vuex A Look at Vue 3 Resources  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Kubernetes Using OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/kubernetes-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/kubernetes-openshift/</guid>
      <description>In this hands-on, virtual workshop, Marek Sadowski will explore how to automate your enterprise application deployment, scaling, and management using Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Kubernetes Using OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/kubernetes-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/kubernetes-openshift/</guid>
      <description>Red Hat OpenShift on IBM Cloud is an extension of the IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service, where IBM manages OpenShift Container Platform for you. With Red Hat OpenShift on IBM Cloud, developers have a fast and secure way to containerize and deploy enterprise workloads in Kubernetes clusters.
OpenShift clusters build on Kubernetes container orchestration that offers consistency and flexibility for your development lifecycle operations.
In this hands-on on-line workshop developers will learn:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAMstack FTW</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/jamstack-ftw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/jamstack-ftw/</guid>
      <description>JAMstack is a web application architecture that has been gaining traction lately. It combines the use of static site generators, JavaScript and APIs and services to create a decoupled site architecture that can improve performance and security. In this free, virtual meetup, Gift Egwuenu will walk through the benefits of JAMstack and show how to create JAMstack sites using Gridsome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamstack FTW- Static Site Generation With Gridsome</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/jamstack-gridsome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/jamstack-gridsome/</guid>
      <description>The Jamstack is the new way of building modern web applications and has evolved over the years. In this session, I&amp;rsquo;ll give an introduction to Gridsome, A static site generator with Vue.js. How we can leverage the Jamstack in building awesome websites with Gridsome also gives the audience a view on what they can achieve with Gridsome. So that by the end of this talk, attendees will understand how to build a website using Gridsome, and all the possibilities they can leverage by using Jamstack to build blazing-fast websites with better performance and great security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Falling in Love with the Command Line and GitHub CLI</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/command-line-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/command-line-github/</guid>
      <description>The command line and GitHub have both become ubiquitous and indespensible tools in almost every developer&amp;rsquo;s workflow. In this virtual meetup, Andrea Griffiths will share some useful tips, ticks and tools that will supercharge your CLI experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love is Blind: Falling in Love with the Command Line and GitHub CLI</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/github-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/github-cli/</guid>
      <description>In a world filled with sexy user interfaces, understanding and even learning to love the command line can be your most understated tool as a developer. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my CLI love story and the reasons why learning to love the command line syntax, basic utilities and file structures has made a better technologist.
At the end of this talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a bag full of neat tricks and CLI tools to improve your workflows and a clear understanding of how GitHub CLI can supercharge your CLI experience&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Serverless Using OpenWhisk - Hands On Workshop</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/get-started-with-openwhisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/get-started-with-openwhisk/</guid>
      <description>Serverless is the new most talked about architecture pattern and quickly becoming a buzz word. The idea is for developers to stop worrying about server management and focus on code. The serverless platform takes care of the provisioning servers, underlying infrastructure, server maintenance security and scaling. We will look at three practical use cases of serverless with example code.
 Secure and Scalable APIs Backend micro services Event driven programming  Key concepts introduced will include triggers, rules, actions, composition and event driven architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Serverless Using OpenWhisk</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/serverless-with-openwhisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/serverless-with-openwhisk/</guid>
      <description>In this free, hands-on workshop, Upkar Lidder of IBM Developer will walk you through building three serverless applications using the open source Apache OpenWhisk platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying PWAs</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/demystifying-pwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/demystifying-pwas/</guid>
      <description>Progressive web apps (PWA) allow for your web apps to have some of the capabilities of mobile apps - like offline availability or the ability to install the app. They have been gaining steam, especially since support on Safari has been improving. In this free online session, Lee Warrick will offer an introduction to PWAs and show you what you need to know to start building one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying PWAs</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/demystifying-pwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/demystifying-pwas/</guid>
      <description>Stop me if you’ve heard this one before, “We need a website, an iOS, and an android app! But… we don’t have that many developers…” It’s tough knowing three languages and ecosystems just to get your app in front of all your users. What if there was a better way? Progressive Web Apps could be the solution to your app woes. PWAs are cross-platform, searchable, opt-in apps that can provide native-like experiences using web technology (JS, React, Vue, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Serverless</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/getting-started-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/getting-started-serverless/</guid>
      <description>We hear the term serverless all the time, but what does it mean and what is it useful for in the real world of developers? In this free session, Upkar Lidder of IBM Developer will introduce the concept of serverless, practical use cases and the key concepts that you need to know to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Serverless</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/getting-started-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/getting-started-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Serverless is the new most talked about architecture pattern and quickly becoming a buzz word. The idea is for developers to stop worrying about server management and focus on code. The serverless platform takes care of the provisioning servers, underlying infrastructure, server maintenance security and scaling. We will look at three practical use cases of serverless with example code.
 Secure and Scalable APIs Backend micro services Event driven programming  Key concepts introduced will include triggers, rules, actions, composition and event driven architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashback Conference</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/flashback-conference-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/flashback-conference-2020/</guid>
      <description>Join us on February 10-11 in Orlando, Florida! Explore new and cutting-edge web development, browser APIs and developer tooling and how they’ve evolved into the web of today. Flashback Conference features 2 days filled with sessions from experts in the field of front-end development and JavaScript.
Topics include:
 JavaScript Web Development Web Standards Serverless    JAMstack Accessibility Browser-based Game Development Developer Community   Register Today!  Don&#39;t miss out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 Rules Redux</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/14-rules-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/14-rules-redux/</guid>
      <description>It’s 2020, and more than ever we live in an age of immediacy. We make demands for speedier processes, or at the very least - less wait times. All industries and services have scrutinized operations in ways to make product delivery as expeditious as possible.
When authoring the influential tool FireBug, Firefox’s Joe Hewitt mentioned measuring load times as an objective. The same year, some equally influential writing was published : “High Performance Web Sites”, a book by Steve Souders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Website Performance</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/improving-website-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/improving-website-performance/</guid>
      <description>The success or failure of a web application is heavily impacted by its performance. As MDN notes, &amp;ldquo;site speed directly affects bounce rates, conversion rates, revenue, user satisfaction, and search engine ranking. Performant sites have been shown to increase visitor retention and user satisfaction.&amp;rdquo; In this free session, Henri Helvetica will explore the rules we&amp;rsquo;ve lived by for the last decade when it comes to web performance and how these rules apply on today&amp;rsquo;s web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Visual Development the Future?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/visual-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/visual-development/</guid>
      <description>Tools like Wix, Squarespace and Webflow are changing the way much of the web is designed and developed. Join us for this free event as Amanda Loftis takes a look at these tools and how they impact web design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Visual Development the Future?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/visual-development-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/visual-development-future/</guid>
      <description>Explore the growing field of visual development and learn how visual coding apps like Wix, Squarespace, and Webflow can be a powerful tool for both novices and experienced web designers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/understand-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/understand-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning is rapidly changing the way we build applications and the kinds of capabilities our apps can have. Join us for this free event as Jen Looper explores the possibilities and limitations of machine learning and natural language processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building IoT Apps (2019) - Course Outline</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-iot-apps-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-iot-apps-2019/</guid>
      <description> Session 1 - A Lap around Particle Lab 1 - Claiming and naming your first device Session 2 - Introducing Particle Primitives, the Device Cloud and Mesh Lab 2 - Set-up a Mesh Network and pipe data to the Particle Device Cloud Session 3 - Going Beyond Devices (Particle Integrations &amp;amp; Azure IoT Central) Lab 3 - Connect your project to Azure IoT Central Session 4 - From the Cloud, back to devices Lab 4 - Bringing it all together  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building IoT Apps with Azure &amp; Particle</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/building-iot-apps-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/building-iot-apps-2019/</guid>
      <description>Please note that the registration deadline of November 13th for the hardware has passed and we can no longer guarantee that hardware will arrive in time for the workshop for new registrants.
Modern connected hardware (or IoT) applications are about more than setting up a microcontroller to read sensors or control actuators. Increasingly, these systems need to connect with other devices, backhaul their data to the cloud, or enable remote updates or commands across large distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Professional Networking for Developers</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/networking-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/networking-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>Becoming a successful networker can be critical in helping any developer find a job or further their careers. However, it isn&amp;rsquo;t always a skill that comes naturally or comfortably to developers. In this session, Wesley Faulkner of MongoDB will share some of his advice on how to get beyond that awkwardness and succeed at professional networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Through the Awkwardness of Networking</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/networking-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/networking-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot about modern networking that we all should un-learn. Showing off your knowledge and targeting the &amp;ldquo;important&amp;rdquo; connections is the wrong approach. If you genuinely want to be an effective networker, you have to shift away from looking at these interactions as transactional. That said, it&amp;rsquo;s still hard to find people to talk to, and even harder to know to start up a conversation. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you tips that will help you work through those issues and ultimately make you more comfortable in new spaces with new people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sextech: The Good, the Bad &amp; the Bias</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/sextech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/sextech/</guid>
      <description>This month we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at an area where a lot of technology innovation is occurring, but where we often don&amp;rsquo;t hear about due to some misconceptions and biases around a sensitive topic - sextech. Join us to learn more about what this area of technology is about much more than what you may imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sextech: The Good, the Bad &amp; the Bias</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/sextech-good-bad-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/sextech-good-bad-bias/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to sextech, people often let their imaginations get in the way of the facts. One common reason is that the media likes to focus primarily on VR porn and bang-able robots. In reality, these subjects are just a small sliver on the sextech spectrum. Sextech spans everything from menopause technology and sex-ed apps to teledildonics and erotica audiobooks. You encounter it when you use an app to track your menstrual cycle, talk to an A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blazor: Silverlight Done Right</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/blazor-silverlight-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/blazor-silverlight-done-right/</guid>
      <description>Over a decade ago, the first version of Silverlight was released and rapidly became a panacea for C# developers to write client web apps. The combination of plug-in free smartphones and evolving HTML5 standards led to its fast demise. From its ashes a new framework has been born that accomplishes what it could not: running .NET, in every modern desktop and phone browser, without plug-ins. Learn about Blazor, a framework for building Single Page Applications (SPA) that uses the power of WebAssembly to bring .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Blazor</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/csharp-blazor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/csharp-blazor/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a ton of buzz in the .NET community lately around Blazor. Unlike many hyped technologies however, Blazor seems to have earned the attention. It earned it in part by delivering a solution that gives C# developers what they want but doing so in a way that relied on open web standards. In this session, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Jeremy Likness will go deeper into what Blazor is, how it works and how you can use it to build web apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aimee Knight</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/aimee-knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/aimee-knight/</guid>
      <description>Aimee Knight is a full-stack software engineer at Tuft &amp;amp; Needle. As a former professional figure skater, she has a tremendous amount of energy and grit. Outside of work, she&amp;rsquo;s a Google Developer Expert in Web Technologies, a panelist on the JavaScript Jabber podcast and an international keynote speaker. Currently, she specializes in JS, React, and CSS, however, she&amp;rsquo;s worked extensively in Angular, Node, and Ruby on Rails as well. Her past community involvement includes being a weekly panelist on the Angular Air podcast, a co-organizer for CharmCityJS, and mentor for Baltimore NodeSchool and Rails Bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alison Falk</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/alison-falk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/alison-falk/</guid>
      <description>Alison is the founder of Women In Tech Pittsburgh and Sex Tech Space, as well as the Managing Director of Women of Sex Tech. She is a previous software engineer with experience in startup and corporate environments. Alison is currently a cybersecurity master’s candidate at the George Washington University and a recipient of the (ISC)2 Center for Cyber Safety and Education award. She has also been awarded the RedChair Pgh scholarship for leadership as a mid-career woman in IT and recognized as one of fourteen individuals shaping Pittsburgh tech scene by The Incline’s Who’s Next in Technology 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alyssa Nicoll</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/alyssa-nicoll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/alyssa-nicoll/</guid>
      <description>Alyssa is an Angular Developer Advocate for KUI and a GDE. Her two degrees (Web Design &amp;amp; Development and Psychology) feed her speaking career. She has spoken at over 30 conferences Internationally. She is a weekly panelist on Adventures in Angular and Angular Air, which have a combined following of over 16,000 listeners. She enjoys gaming, scuba diving, and has a newborn that fondly goes by &amp;ldquo;Mr. Milks&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanda Loftis</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/amanda-loftis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/amanda-loftis/</guid>
      <description>Amanda is the UX Director at Fluree, a blockchain database provider. She has designed print, web, and native application experiences. In her free time, you can find her beekeeping, trying to keep her plants alive, and making beer labels for her dad&amp;rsquo;s homebrews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrea Griffiths</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/andrea-griffiths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/andrea-griffiths/</guid>
      <description>Andrea Griffiths is a Community Support Hype Woman with over a decade experience in customer management, success and support. Currently a Community Specialist at GitHub, Andrea is customer obsessed, and an effective advocate for all users. Andrea is a super fan of OSS and the unlimited power of community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy Barnov</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/andy-barnov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/andy-barnov/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a switch from a 15-year long career as an international TV reporter, Andy taught himself programming and got his Ruby/Rails bases covered by graduating from Le Wagon bootcamp in Paris. While pursuing a Computer Science degree in Amsterdam, Andy enjoys teaching beginners to code at various Wagon schools in Europe.
Rubotnik is his pet project that allows anyone with a minimal programming knowledge to quickly launch a functional (and framework independent) Facebook Messenger bot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayan George</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/ayan-george/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/ayan-george/</guid>
      <description>Ayan&amp;rsquo;s first home computers was a Commodore Vic 20 in the early 80s. He started programming in C in middle school. He worked in the ISP, petroleum, digital signal processing, and operating systems industries and has also been a business owner.
Ayan was introduced to Go in 2011 but fell in love with it in the last 4 years or so. He organizes the Orlando Go meetup and is currently CTO of a stealth startup, a father, husband, and an avid photographer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayşegül Yönet</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/aysegul-yonet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/aysegul-yonet/</guid>
      <description>Aysegul is a Senior Azure Cloud Developer Advocate at Microsoft. Aysegul, focuses on Spatial Computing, Mixed Reality, AI, Angular and Data Visualization. She is a Google Developer Expert for Web Technologies &amp;amp; Angular and an active conference speaker. She previously worked as Senior Software Engineer at Nrwl.io, Autodesk Play, a 3D and VR authoring tool and A360 Viewer and A360 Drive. She enjoys teaching at a variety of non-profit organizations aiming to increase diversity in the software industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Ilegbodu</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/ben-ilegbodu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/ben-ilegbodu/</guid>
      <description>Ben is a Christian, husband and father of 3, with nearly 15 years of professional experience developing user interfaces for the Web. He currently is a Principal Frontend Engineer at Eventbrite, focused on increasing the success of event creators through data and recommendations. Ben also is a Google Developer Expert, Microsoft MVP, and enjoys playing basketball, DIY, watching movies, and tweeting (@benmvp) / blogging (benmvp.com) about his experiences with new web technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bianca Gandolfo</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/bianca-gandolfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/bianca-gandolfo/</guid>
      <description>Bianca is a software engineer at Thumbtack who has written and taught on Frontend Masters, Pluralsight and at various coding Bootcamps throughout the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brad Marsh</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brad-marsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brad-marsh/</guid>
      <description>Brad is a Senior Developer at SmartThings, who has spent the last 11 years focusing on user experience driven development. For the past 3 years, his primary focus has been on finding better and more intuitive ways for people to interact with their homes. An avid writer, as well as programmer, he founded LitLift.com, a novel planning website which he sold in 2013. Currently he spends his free time doing game development and cooking BBQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brandon Satrom</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brandon-satrom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brandon-satrom/</guid>
      <description>Brandon Satrom is the Developer Evangelist for Particle. An unabashed lover of the web, mobile and an avid tinkerer, Brandon loves to talk about sensors and circuits, microcontrollers, open source, robots and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brian Leroux</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brian-leroux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/brian-leroux/</guid>
      <description>Brian LeRoux is the Cofounder/CTO of begin.com which is a new breed of app that helps teams stay organized in Slack. In the process of developing begin.com an entirely serverless cloud functions thing emerged called arc.codes. In a former life Brian worked at Adobe on PhoneGap and its open source upstream Apache Cordova. A longtime fan of the open web he created wtfjs.com and sports a questionable &amp;amp;nbsp; tattoo. Brian believes the future is mobile, seamlessly running in the cloud, on open source software and will be created by hackers like you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke Holland</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/burke-holland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/burke-holland/</guid>
      <description>Burke Holland is a front-end developer in Nashville, TN, working on the Azure team at Microsoft. Burke blogs only slightly better than he codes but not as good as he talks about himself in the 3rd person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carlos Souza</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/carlos-souza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/carlos-souza/</guid>
      <description>Carlos Souza is a Pluralsight author, consultant and community organizer. When not making loud noises with his mechanical keyboard, he can be found playing music or rock climbing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Coyier</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/chris-coyier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/chris-coyier/</guid>
      <description>Chris is a web designer and developer. He writes about all things web at CSS-Tricks, talks about all things web at conferences around the world and on his podcast ShopTalk, and co-founded CodePen, a social development environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christina Aldan</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/christina-aldan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/christina-aldan/</guid>
      <description>Christina Aldan is a TEDx speaker, trainer, and digital advertising consultant whose boutique agency, LG Designs, offers businesses brand consulting and creative content for everyday media. She currently serves as Marketing Coordinator for Starmark1 and has sat on state and local boards supporting women in tech, entrepreneurship and children with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Khourshid</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/david-khourshid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/david-khourshid/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diana Rodriguez</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/diana-rodriguez/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/diana-rodriguez/</guid>
      <description>Diana Rodriguez is a Full Stack Developer/DevOps &amp;amp; Google Developer Expert. With 18 years&amp;rsquo; experience and a strong background in back end and infrastructure, Diana likes to bring together the best of both worlds, spreading DevOps culture. She&amp;rsquo;s super enthusiastic about everything to encourage people to start a career in development and a fan of female devs and DevOps. In her spare time she likes to play videogames, also a huge fan of sports, Diana is a rugby player and taekwondo black belt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divya Tagtachian</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/divya-tagtachian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/divya-tagtachian/</guid>
      <description>Divya is a web developer who is passionate about open source and the web. She is currently a developer advocate at Netlify, and believes that there is a better workflow for building and deploying sites that doesn’t require a server—ask her about the JAMstack. You will most likely find her in the sunniest spot in the room with a cup of tea in hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Em Lazer-Walker</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/em-lazer-walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/em-lazer-walker/</guid>
      <description>Em is a Cloud Advocate at Microsoft based in Toronto. She’s an artist and engineer who makes interactive art, experimental games, and open-source software tools to empower creativity. Most of her work focuses on using nontraditional interfaces to reframe everyday objects and spaces as playful experiences and to inspire people to become self-motivated learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estelle Weyl</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/estelle-weyl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/estelle-weyl/</guid>
      <description>Estelle is a consulting web developer, trainer, author and speaker, currently writing for MDN Web Docs on accessibility, web performance, HTML, JS, and CSS, including Houdini. She speaks and leads workshops on web development all over the world. Her books have been translated into over 14 languages. She’s been coding CSS, HTML, and JavaScript since 1999.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gift Egwuenu</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/gift-egwuenu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/gift-egwuenu/</guid>
      <description>Gift Egwuenu is a frontend engineer and technical writer based in Lagos, Nigeria. She is passionate about making the web accessible to everyone and also an advocate for building open-source projects and she enjoys solving complex problems using web technologies. She is also passionate about building communities which led her to start the Vue Vixens chapter in Nigeria and the JAMstack community in Lagos. She is also a co-organizer for Concatenate Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helena McCabe</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/helena-mccabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/helena-mccabe/</guid>
      <description>When she was 11 years old, Helena picked up a book on HTML at the library and started making websites for fun. After being paid primarily in pizza and other miscellaneous barters for a little over a decade, she turned her swapportunity-filled hobby into a career and started working in the web development field professionally.
Over the past five years of writing code at Lullabot, she’s worked as a front-end developer on big media brands such as Syfy, MSNBC, and the GRAMMYs, often leading the front-end on large-scale implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henri Helvetica</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/henri-helvetica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/henri-helvetica/</guid>
      <description>Henri is a freelance developer who has turned his interests to a passionate mix of site performance engineering and pinches of user experience. When not reading the deluge of daily research docs and case studies, or indiscriminately auditing sites in devtools, Henri can be found contributing back to the community, co-programming meetups including the Toronto Web Performance Group or volunteering his time for lunch and learns at various bootcamps. Otherwise, he’s riding track bikes, tooling with music production software or more recently, focusing on the fastest 5k possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holly Schinsky</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/holly-schinsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/holly-schinsky/</guid>
      <description>Holly is a software engineer at Adobe. In her free time she’s usually found running, driving a carpool or hanging out with her family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Thomas</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/james-thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/james-thomas/</guid>
      <description>ames is a Developer Advocate for IBM Bluemix, helping developers build scalable applications on IBM’s cloud platform. Working with the Emerging Technologies division, James has been a leading open-source developer for a JavaScript toolkit before working on the first commercial system for IBM Watson as the UI Technical Lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jay Hoffmann</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jay-hoffmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jay-hoffmann/</guid>
      <description>Jay is the lead developer at Reaktiv Studios, a WordPress centered development shop focused on custom solutions and complex integrations. He has been a developer for over a decade, and has previously worked at Sesame Workshop and Penguin Random House. His passion for the web stretches back even further to an early age, and his first glimpse had him instantly hooked. In 2017, he created the newsletter and blog The History of the Web, which combines his love of the World Wide Web and history into both short and long-form posts, updated regularly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jem Young</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jem-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jem-young/</guid>
      <description>Jem Young is an engineer at Netflix who really enjoys working across the stack but his true passion lies in JavaScript and building a clean user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jen Looper</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jen-looper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jen-looper/</guid>
      <description>Jen Looper is a Google Developer Expert and a Cloud Developer Advocate Lead at Microsoft with over 18 years&amp;rsquo; experience as a web and mobile developer, specializing in creating cross-platform mobile apps. She&amp;rsquo;s a multilingual multiculturalist with a passion for hardware hacking, mobile apps, Vue.js, machine learning and discovering new things every day. She is the founder and CEO of Vue Vixens, an initiative promoting diversity in the Vue.js community. Visit her online at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenell Pizarro</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jenell-pizarro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jenell-pizarro/</guid>
      <description>Jenell is a Sass-slinging, semantic markup loving, micro-interaction obsessed UX Developer at Capco. She loves the development community, getting excited about new front end resources, and roller skating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeremy Likness</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jeremy-likness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jeremy-likness/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy Likness (@JeremyLikness on Twitter) wrote his first program in 1981 and has been paid to code for over 25 years. The focus for most of his career has been delivering line of business applications in roles ranging from developer, manager, director and owner to consultant, trainer, and mentor. He currently works as a cloud advocate in developer relations at Microsoft. Jeremy is an international and keynote speaker, the author of several internationally-selling technical books, and a prolific blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jo Franchetti</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jo-franchetti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jo-franchetti/</guid>
      <description>Jo is a Developer Advocate at Ably Realtime who is passionate about VR, Web Bluetooth, PWAs and great CSS. She’s got 6 years experience as a web developer and has worked in various parts of the tech industry from startups, agencies, charities to large organizations. She is also mentor and organizer at codebar.io where she is able to action her passion not only for teaching good use of the web but also for improving the diversity and inclusivity of the tech industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnny Boursiquot</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/johnny-boursiquot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/johnny-boursiquot/</guid>
      <description>Johnny Boursiquot is author of the Go Standard Library Solutions available from Packt Publishing. Johnny is a Site Reliability Engineer at Salesforce’s Heroku and enjoys teaching Go and cloud architecture. As an active member of the Go community, he runs the Baltimore Metro Area Go User Group, leads the Baltimore Chapter of the GoBridge organization, and teaches regularly at technology conferences and meetups. He loves welcoming new members into the Go community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jory Burson</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jory-burson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/jory-burson/</guid>
      <description>Jory is a consultant and educator working to improve collaboration in open source and open standards communities as a member of several industry boards and standards setting organizations. She is sponsored by Bocoup to advocate for web developers on Ecma International&amp;rsquo;s Executive Committee, the JS Foundation Technical Architecture Committee, the W3C Advisory Council, the MDN Product Advisory Board, and works on projects with Ecma TC39, Ecma TC53, and Web Platform Tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kent C. Dodds</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/kent-c-dodds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/kent-c-dodds/</guid>
      <description>Kent C. Dodds is a world renowned speaker, teacher, and trainer and he&amp;rsquo;s actively involved in the open source community as a maintainer and contributor of hundreds of popular npm packages. Kent is the creator of TestingJavaScript.com and he&amp;rsquo;s an instructor on egghead.io and Frontend Masters. He&amp;rsquo;s also a Google Developer Expert. Kent is happily married and the father of four kids. He likes his family, code, JavaScript, and React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyle Simpson</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/kyle-simpson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/kyle-simpson/</guid>
      <description>Kyle is an evangelist of the Open Web, and passionate about all things JavaScript. He writes, speaks, teaches, and contributes to OSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lee Warrick</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/lee-warrick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/lee-warrick/</guid>
      <description>Lee Warrick is a Full-Stack Developer with Realtruck.com, organizer of Project Codex: Orlando’s Junior Developer Meetup, Co-Host of the Tech Jr Podcast, and all-around Junior Developer Advocate. Being a career-changer himself, Lee has made it his mission to pay forward all of the help he received as a new developer ten-fold, and improve the lives of new developers in any way he can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marek Sadowski</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/marek-sadowski/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/marek-sadowski/</guid>
      <description>Marek Sadowski is a full stack developer advocate, a robotics startup founder and an entrepreneur. He has about 20 year experience in consulting largest enterprises in USA, Europe, Japan, Middle East and Africa. As a graduate from the International Space University, Marek pioneered in a research on VR goggles for the virtual reality system to control robots on Mars in NASA Ames. He founded a startup to deliver robotics solutions and services for industries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Thengvall</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/mary-thengvall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/mary-thengvall/</guid>
      <description>Mary Thengvall is a connector of people at heart, both personally and professionally. She loves digging into the strategy of how to build and foster developer communities and has been doing so for over 10 years. In addition to her work, she&amp;rsquo;s known for being &amp;ldquo;the one with the dog,&amp;rdquo; thanks to her ever-present medical alert service dog Ember. She&amp;rsquo;s the author of the first book on Developer Relations: The Business Value of Developer Relations (© 2018, Apress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalia Tepluhina</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/natalia-tepluhina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/natalia-tepluhina/</guid>
      <description>Natalia Tepluhina is a Vue.js core team member and a Senior Frontend Engineer at GitLab.
She is a conference speaker and author of articles on different topics related to Vue.js . Thanks to these activities Natalia has got a title of Google Developer Expert in Web Technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick Walsh</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/nick-walsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/nick-walsh/</guid>
      <description>As a Technical Evangelist for Amazon Web Services, Nick works to empower developers everywhere. Nick is passionate about making interactive and accessible educational content for developers, showcasing how they can leverage AWS services in order to focus on building what they truly care about.
Nick has worked to build developer tools across multiple organizations (Wolfram Research, Datmo, and now AWS) that power artificial intelligence and machine learning capabilities in applications. Having worked at nearly every level of abstraction in the ML/AI service space, Nick has helped startups and enterprises alike integrate AI into their production applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paige Bailey</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/paige-bailey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/paige-bailey/</guid>
      <description>Paige Bailey is the product manager for Swift for TensorFlow.
Prior to her role as a PM in Google Brain, Paige was developer advocate for TensorFlow core; a senior software engineer and machine learning engineer in the office of the Microsoft Azure CTO; and a data scientist at Chevron. Her academic research was focused on lunar ultraviolet, at the Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics (LASP) in Boulder, CO, as well as Southwest Research Institute (SwRI) in San Antonio, TX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul DeCarlo</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/paul-decarlo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/paul-decarlo/</guid>
      <description>Paul DeCarlo is a Microsoft Cloud Advocate and Professor for the Bauer College of Business at the University of Houston. His technology interests are Internet of Things, cloud applications and cross-platform mobile development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phil Hawksworth</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/phil-hawksworth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/phil-hawksworth/</guid>
      <description>Phil is Principal Developer Experience Engineer at Netlify. With a passion for browser technologies and the empowering properties of the web, he loves seeking out ingenuity and simplicity, especially in places where over-engineering is common. After more than 20 years of building web applications for companies such as Google, Apple, Nike, R/GA, and The London Stock Exchange, Phil has worked to challenge traditional technical architectures in favour of simplicity and effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PWA, How Did We Get Here?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/pwa-how-did-we-get-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/pwa-how-did-we-get-here/</guid>
      <description>Back in the mid 90&amp;rsquo;s we only had one cross platform choice for building internet connected applications and that was HTML, CSS and JavaScript. So why is it now that after 25+ years have passed we are back to building internet connected applications with HTML, CSS and JavaScript and calling them Progressive Web Apps? Join me as we journey from the webs earliest beginnings to get back exactly where we started, or have we?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raymond Camden</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/raymond-camden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/raymond-camden/</guid>
      <description>Raymond Camden works as a Lead Developer Evangelist for HERE Technologies. He works on serverless, JavaScript, web standards, and enterprise cat demos. He is the author of multiple books on web development and has been actively blogging and presenting for almost twenty years. Raymond can be reached at his blog, @raymondcamden on Twitter, or via email at raymondcamden@gmail.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizchel Wood</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/rizchel-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/rizchel-wood/</guid>
      <description>Development isn’t just about making products. It’s about making an impact. That’s Rizchel Dayao’s goal: to make a difference through technology.
Rizchel started her career at IBM. She worked her way up from being a front-end developer, to a team leader, to a Developer Advocate. In that role, she spoke at conferences and created content about emerging technologies like Kubernetes, serverless computing, and container architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Wozniak</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/robert-wozniak/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/robert-wozniak/</guid>
      <description>Robert is a passionate programmer, husband and a leader. He strives to engage himself in challenging projects by following the motto of &amp;ldquo;Be a better developer today than you were yesterday.&amp;rdquo; He works at TruPull and is also working as an Invited Expert at the W3C, specifically in the Web Payments group to represent and have a part in implementing the future of online transactions. You can find Robert&amp;rsquo;s blog at robertwozniak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Witalec</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/sebastian-witalec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/sebastian-witalec/</guid>
      <description>Sebastian Witalec is a Senior Developer Advocate for Progress who specializes in Angular and NativeScript. He loves working on both serious and fun projects and one day he will use his robot army to conquer the world.
He is always happy to learn about the new stuff and to pass the knowledge as far as his voice (or the wire) can take him. Sebastian is based in London actively working with various Dev communities in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Soper</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/shannon-soper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/shannon-soper/</guid>
      <description>Shannon works doing UX research at GatsbyJS. She is a Utah native who enjoys teaching aand performing music and keeping up with her dog’s Instagram fans. She teaches college-level writing on the side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Vettes</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/shannon-vettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/shannon-vettes/</guid>
      <description>Shannon is a swiss-army-knife who has worked in all things from project management to product management and basically everything in-between. She is an entrepreneur at heart who loves to dive into the tough questions. This has led her down many paths of conflict, and she hopes this panel will allow her to share a little of what she has learned in her trial-by-fire professional life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simon MacDonald</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/simon-macdonald/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/simon-macdonald/</guid>
      <description>Simon has over twenty years of development experience and has worked on a variety of projects including object oriented databases, police communication systems, speech recognition and unified messaging. His current focus is being a developer advocate for Adobe where he assists people building solutions across a wide variety of areas like web, mobile and serverless. Simon’s been building web applications since the days they were written using shell scripts and he still has nightmares about those dark days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tammy Everts</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tammy-everts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tammy-everts/</guid>
      <description>Tammy has spent the past two decades studying how people use the web. Since 2009, she’s focused on the intersection between web performance, user experience, and business metrics. Her book Time Is Money: The Business Value of Web Performance (O’Reilly, 2016) is a distillation of much of this research (but there’s always more to be learned).
Tammy is a frequent speaker at events like Shop.org, IRCE, and Smashing Conference. She also co-curates WPOstats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tara Manicsic</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tara-manicsic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tara-manicsic/</guid>
      <description>Tara Z. Manicsic is a lifelong student, teacher, and maker. She has spent her career using JavaScript on both back-end and front-end to create applications. A Developer Advocate for Progress, Google Developer Expert, and international technical speaker, she focuses on conveying the codebase she has learned. In her free time she works in her community to educate and learn from other developers. Tara launched the Cincinnati Chapter of Women Who Code and the Cincinnati branch of NodeSchool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Humble Radio Button</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/humble-radio-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/humble-radio-button/</guid>
      <description>The radio button may seem antiquated, but it is really just misunderstood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TJ VanToll</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tj-vantoll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tj-vantoll/</guid>
      <description>TJ VanToll is a front-end developer, author, and a senior developer advocate for Progress who spends his time helping web developers build mobile apps through projects like Cordova and NativeScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomomi Imura</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tomomi-imura/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/tomomi-imura/</guid>
      <description>Tomomi Imura (a.k.a girlie_mac) is an avid open web &amp;amp; open technology advocate, who is currently working for Developer Relations team at Slack in San Francisco, also an advisor for Code Chrysalis in Tokyo. Previously, she had worked in the mobile industry at various companies and communities for years, including The World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) to improve mobile web. When she is not at work, she still hacking things, as well as combining technology with cats- her past projects include HTTP Status Cats, and Raspberry Pi Cat Camera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upkar Lidder</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/upkar-lidder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/upkar-lidder/</guid>
      <description>Upkar Lidder is a Full Stack Developer and Data Wrangler with a decade of development experience in a variety of roles. He can be seen speaking at various conferences and participating in local tech groups and meetups. He is currently curious about magic behind Machine Learning and Deep Learning, specifically use of NLP in chatbots. Upkar went to graduate school in Canada and currently resides in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wesley Faulkner</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/speakers/wesley-faulkner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/speakers/wesley-faulkner/</guid>
      <description>Wesley Faulkner is a first-generation American. He is a founding member of the government transparency group Open Austin and ran for Austin City Council in 2016. His professional experience also includes work as a social media and community manager for the software company Atlassian, and various roles for the computer processor company AMD and Dell. Wesley Faulkner serves as a board member for South by Southwest Interactive (SXSWi) and works as Developer Advocate for MongoDB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Relations: Advocates, Evangelists, and Avocados</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/developer-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/developer-relations/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard the term &amp;ldquo;Developer Relations&amp;rdquo; being used in the last year or two and there&amp;rsquo;s a high chance that someone you follow on Twitter just announced that they joined Microsoft or Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Cloud Developer Advocate team&amp;rdquo; but what does this actually mean, and more importantly, why should you care? After all, you just want to commit your code and keep the API up and running. Mary Thengvall, Author of The Business Value of Developer Relations and an experienced Technical Community Manager will explain the difference between Advocates, Evangelists, and Avocados, as well as help you understand how to interact with this new group of folks in a way that is beneficial to everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why DevRel Matters</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/developer-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/developer-relations/</guid>
      <description>Developer Relations and developer advocates have gone from being that rare &amp;ldquo;nice to have&amp;rdquo; that only a handful of companies could afford, to a requirement for most companies that need to connect with developers as consumers of their products and services. Nonetheless, it is still an often misunderstood practice - seen as someone who simply jets around from one conference party to another. In this session, Mary Thengvall will discuss what developer relations is and why it matters to developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Vue</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/introduction-to-vue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/introduction-to-vue/</guid>
      <description>Raymond Camden will give a gentle introduction to the Vue.js framework and describe why he loves it in a completely fair and balanced manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Vue</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/intro-to-vue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/intro-to-vue/</guid>
      <description>Vue is one of the hottest front-end frameworks right now. It is the top trending project overall in the yearly JavaScipt Rising Stars and earlier this year became the second most starred project on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely something every front-end or JavaScript developer should be familiar with. Thankfully, Raymond Camden will give us the rundown on how to get started using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Mixed Reality</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/mixed-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/mixed-reality/</guid>
      <description>In virtual reality, we replace the user&amp;rsquo;s physical world with another entirely. This has important use cases. However, augmented reality and mixed reality applications build upon the user&amp;rsquo;s real-world environment to create a hybrid reality where real world objects and virtual objects coexist. This opens up a whole new set of application possibilities where the user can still interact with their surroundings, but enhanced with information.
In this session, Ayşegül Yönet will explore VR, AR and Mixed Reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Mixed Reality for Good</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/exploring-mixed-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/exploring-mixed-reality/</guid>
      <description>Is VR going to happen? Is Augmented Reality just a buzzword? What is this Mixed Reality anyway? What can Mixed Reality offer that other mediums can&amp;rsquo;t? Join us if you are wondering what good can Mixed Reality technologies achieve and how to get started creating them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Chatbot: The Crash Course</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-a-chatbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-a-chatbot/</guid>
      <description>What are the usual challenges when building one and how to build a chatbot that people would love to interact with?
Then this session is for you. We will look at various possible conversations and challenges that go with them, and look at how they could be improved to keep the users engaged. But more importantly, you will learn how to build a fully functioning chatbot in less than 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chatbot Crash Course</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/chat-bots-crash-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/chat-bots-crash-course/</guid>
      <description>Natural language interfaces often called &amp;ldquo;bots&amp;rdquo; have become ubiquitous, whether they are text or voice. But building a bot that feels natural and easy-to-use for the end user can seem daunting. In this session, Sebastian Witalec is going to go over the fundamentals of building a chatbot to help you get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Go - Course Outline</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-go/</guid>
      <description> Introduction: Serverless Orchestration on AWS (15 minutes) Demo and walkthrough of the serverless app architecture (15 minutes) Getting to know SAM: Serverless Application Model (15 minutes) Hands On: Deploying your serverless stack (30 minutes) Writing Lambda Functions in Go (30 minutes) Hands On: Writing and testing your Go Lambdas (35 minutes) Orchestrating Lambda with Step Functions and SQS (15 minutes) Hands On: Bringing it all together and updating your serverless stack (15 minutes) Q&amp;amp;A and Wrap-up (10 minutes)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Go!</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/serverless-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/serverless-go/</guid>
      <description>Soon after you decide to embrace serverless architectures you realize that there is a need to coordinate all of the components that make up these distributed applications and services. In this course you will stitch together a series of Lambda functions written in the Go programming language (golang) to build and orchestrate a fully-functional and scalable serverless application while learning how to handle the deployment, logging, metric collection, and distributed tracing that help you effectively adopt the serverless way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfectionism, Impostor Syndrome and Anxiety - Understanding your fears and learning to be kind to yourself</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Working in the tech industry can sometimes make us feel inferior. It is easy to start believing that everyone knows more, or finds the work easier. When we’re surrounded by so many intelligent people, how can we not start to judge ourselves against them and our work against theirs? Impostor syndrome - the belief that you don’t deserve to be where you are, and perfectionism - a need to work to impossibly high standards, are exhausting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with Perfectionism, Imposter Syndrome &amp; Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Imposter syndrome, anxiety and perfectionism are not issues that only face people working in tech, but they do seem to inordinately affect people working in tech at some time or another in their careers. In this session, Jo Franchetti discusses how to spot these patterns in yourself and offers strategies to deal with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Patterns in UI — What not to do to your users</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/dark-ui-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/dark-ui-patterns/</guid>
      <description>I believe developers of any caliber and framework could benefit from knowing more about the power we have as developers over usability and how we can use that power for good.
In this talk, I will go over some very obvious (and some not so obvious) patterns that are used online to manipulate users. Understanding usability gives us a lot of power as web designers/developers. We should use this knowledge for good, rather than tricking users into un-intended behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fostering Your Local JavaScript Community</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/fostering-local-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/fostering-local-community/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, Carlos Souza will share some of his experience facilitating user groups for the last decade. Over this period, technology has drastically changed and it continues to constantly evolve. JavaScript, more specifically, has gone from a simple tool used to animate websites to being the main engine which powers enterprise-grade systems. This presentation will cover lessons learned from fostering a community of technologically-likeminded people and thoughts on what this community might look like in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOUC, and the Death of Progressive Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/fouc-progressive-enhancement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/fouc-progressive-enhancement/</guid>
      <description>Web developers have long heralded Progressive Enhancement for delivering web experiences in “layers” (HTML, images, CSS, and then JS). It sounds so obvious and elegant, right? But FOUC (Flash of Unstyled Content) exposes the lies we’ve been telling ourselves and users!
It’s time to peel back the layers and re-envision how the web is assembled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From DHTML to CSS Variables</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/dhtml-to-css-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/dhtml-to-css-variables/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 3 decades, the way we animate on the web has evolved. Flash died, JavaScript matured, and CSS became more powerful. In this talk, we will rediscover web animation of years past and explore future innovations and trends in creating dynamic, highly interactive, multi-modal web experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of WebXR API&#39;s and Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/future-of-webxr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/future-of-webxr/</guid>
      <description>We are gathering more data than ever before. Are we able to analyze and learn from it? Are we able to access the data in the right context? We have a lot of ways to analyze and visualize data on the web today. Now we have the capability to have the visualizations and data we need at the right time and right place. WebXR APIs allow us to create Augmented Reality applications that can integrate the virtual data into our world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamstack Hits the Spot</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/jamstack-hits-the-spot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/jamstack-hits-the-spot/</guid>
      <description>Static sites have made a comeback as of late. This “return to simplicity’ is unsurprising given the current complexity of websites and applications that make maintenance quite the nightmare. Regardless, static sites today are a far cry from their older counterparts. Static sites circa early 2000s consisted of static markup with some CSS thrown in for flavor. Today, static sites are much more dynamic and are a healthy mix of JavaScript, APIs and Markup, aka JAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s web dev like it’s 1999! 🎉</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/webdev-like-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/webdev-like-1999/</guid>
      <description>When we “view source” our modern web applications, the code looks nothing like what we originally wrote. At a minimum, it’s gone through linting, transpilation, obfuscation, minification, and bundling. And in order to build our beautifully designed apps with sophisticated interactions, we leverage the latest features in HTML, CSS and JavaScript available in our modern evergreen browsers.
However, when web development was in its infancy two decades ago, things were drastically different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling a Live Battle Royale Game With No Budget</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/scaling-battle-royale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/scaling-battle-royale/</guid>
      <description>When my collaborator and I built a silly online HTML5 multiplayer game as an open-source side project — Flappy Royale is a 100-player battle royale version of Flappy Bird — we didn’t expect it to go viral. But when we found ourselves going from 0 to nearly 200,000 daily users in just three days, we also found ourselves facing equivalently huge server stability issues and server costs. This talk will walk through our journey rearchitecting Flappy Royale’s backend services, and what we learned building a low-cost, low-maintenance backend for a live HTML5 multiplayer game without a dedicated operations team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dynamic Web, from CGI to Serverless</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/cgi-to-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/cgi-to-serverless/</guid>
      <description>A look at the history of adding dynamic aspects to web sites, from Apache server-side includes and Perl CGI scripts to app servers (ColdFusion, ASP, PHP) to modern JAMStack sites using serverless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly of Serverless Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/good-bad-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/good-bad-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Outside of micro-services, far away from event triggers and message queues, a growing contingent of web developers are on a mission: to make the web serverless. But I&amp;rsquo;m a skeptic. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even sure what &amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo; actually means or whether or not any of this is even a good idea. But I also know that once the web adopts something, the rest is history. So I did what developers do when they want answers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Accessibility: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/web-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/web-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>Web accessibility has been around for a long time, but it’s only become a mainstream topic of conversation in the past few years. In this session, we’ll take a look at where we’ve come from, where we are today, and what the future might hold for accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Happened to the Webmaster?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/what-happened-webmaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/what-happened-webmaster/</guid>
      <description>The webmaster was once, quite literally, the master of their domain. Whatever request came through for the website, they could handle, be it a HTML tweak or fix to the server. Their skills evolved with the web, and there was very little they couldn&amp;rsquo;t handle. Self-taught and always learning, the best sites around had a dedicated webmaster or two.
Then, sometime in the last 20 years, the webmaster disappeared. Amidst the new world of Web 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Enterprise Applications with the Magic of React, Redux, and GraphQL</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/enterprise-react-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/enterprise-react-apps/</guid>
      <description>Many of us are working on enterprise applications but I often find myself frustrated and lost with how to architect an application in the beginning. There are many things we have to worry about when building large applications especially with large volumes of data and configurations. How do we know what to focus on and where to start while keeping best practices and optimum performance in mind? In this talk, I will go over the journey we went through to create an enterprise application from the ground up for the IBM Cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript for Enterprise Development</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/enterprise-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/enterprise-javascript/</guid>
      <description>For years, JavaScript was dismissed as &amp;ldquo;not enterprise ready,&amp;rdquo; but those days have long past. Modern tools and frameworks have made JavaScript a mainstay in the enterprise. In this free online meetup, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a couple of ways that JavaScript can be utilized in enterprise development. Join Rizchel Dayao presenting &amp;ldquo;Building Enterprise Applications with the Magic of React, Redux, and GraphQL&amp;rdquo; and Simon MacDonald presenting &amp;ldquo;The FaaS and the Serverless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The FaaS and the Serverless</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/faas-and-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/faas-and-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever notice that FasS &amp;amp; Serverless is a lot like the Fast &amp;amp; the Furious series of movies? Each of the different characters is like a function specializing in doing one thing really well. Then when when you combine their abilities as a team they can accomplish anything like a great app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has Web Development Become Difficult?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/web-development-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/web-development-difficult/</guid>
      <description>Developers have never had more tools at their disposal, but has this explosion of tools also made web development difficult? Have we erected new barriers to entry for anyone looking to break into a career in web development?
In this free online meetup, Jory Burson will explore the question of when and how web development became so complicated by looking at the evolution of the industry. Then Raymond Camden will explore some of the tools out there designed to help developers learn new skills and highlight some of the pros and cons of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Web Your Own Way</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/learning-web-your-own-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/learning-web-your-own-way/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an incredible amount of things a web developer needs to know with new things being released every day. How does a new developer even begin to learn? How do they keep up? In this talk, Raymond will discuss various different options, pros and cons of each, and introduce you to some options you may not have heard of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why&#39;d you have to go and make things so complicated?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/webdev-complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/webdev-complicated/</guid>
      <description>Learning web development from scratch can be a daunting task. In addition to programming languages, there are all kinds of tools it seems you need to master just to get started: bundlers, taskrunners, package managers, transpilers… when and how did web development get to be so complicated? In this talk, we&amp;rsquo;ll follow the evolution of a web page through time, introducing it to technical obstacles and innovations until we arrive at present day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a SQL Helper Library in Go</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/sql-helper-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/sql-helper-go/</guid>
      <description>Go has an SQL package as part of its standard library. There are also a few ORM-like and SQL helper libraries that wrap the standard SQL package. In this talk, Ayan will demonstrate how easy it is to implement something similar yourself and demonstrate the power of Go&amp;rsquo;s type system and richness of Go&amp;rsquo;s standard library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Great with Go</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/going-great-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/going-great-with-go/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few years Go has developed a strong and growing following. IEEE lists it both as one of the top 10 programming languages in 2018, but also as one of its top 5 trending languages. In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll get to know the Go language better by exploring how to us it to do things like build serverless applications and connect to complex data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrating Serverless Go Applications on AWS</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-go-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-go-aws/</guid>
      <description>Soon after you decide to embrace serverless architectures you realize the need to coordinate all of the components of your distributed apps and services. In this talk we’ll stitch together a series of Lambda functions written in the Go programming language (golang) to build a serverless Slack command while demonstrating the deployment, logging, metric collection, and distributed tracing that help you effectively adopt the serverless way. You’ll not only pick up some Go, you’ll also see tools like AWS SAM CLI, API Gateway, and Step Functions in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Payments</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/future-of-web-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/future-of-web-payments/</guid>
      <description>Building a checkout process is almost a right of passage for a web developer, but, unfortunately, it has often been difficult and complicated to do. Part of the problem was that, even though this was a common requirement, there was no standard way to implement payments on the web. The good news is, that is changing. In this session, Robert Wozniak, Invited Expert at the W3C, will discuss new APIs that will help standardize the way we handle payments in the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Web Payments - The Payment Request and Payment Handler APIs</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/payment-request-handler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/payment-request-handler/</guid>
      <description>Did you ever think about rising costs of spending too much time on implementing checkouts?
During this presentation, we&amp;rsquo;ll to walk through the future of web payments in the browser. We&amp;rsquo;ll put a spotlight on different ways of implementing native, secure and bug-free checkouts. What does this mean for you? It means lower costs of implementation and less time spent on development. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover how to implement the Payment Request and Payment Handler APIs and talk about the advantages, use cases and ways to use them efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/ethics-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/ethics-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>As engineers, the decisions we make often have real world consequences but we&amp;rsquo;re often too far removed to understand the impact of our decisions. As an industry, we need to have more candid and frank discussions about the ethics and morality of the tools we build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics in Software Engineering - Panel Discussion</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/ethics-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/ethics-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Join a panel featuring members of the Front End Happy Hour podcast as they discuss and debate topics related to ethics in software engineering. Join in the discussion via the chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building IoT Apps (2018) - Course Outline</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-iot-apps-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/building-iot-apps-2018/</guid>
      <description> Introduction and Housekeeping Introducing the Particle Ecosystem (Brandon) [30 minutes] Hands On: Getting your Device connected (Brandon) [15 minutes] The Particle Device OS and Cloud Services (Brandon) [30 minutes] Hands On: Publishing Device Info to the Particle Cloud (Brandon) [15 minutes] An Introduction to the Azure IoT Hub (Burke) [30 minutes] Hands On: IoT Hub (Burke) [15 minutes] Data Visualization with Azure (Burke) [30 minutes] Hands On: Azure (Burke) [15 minutes] Controlling your devices from the Cloud (Burke and Brandon) [15 minutes] Hands On: Bringing it all together (Burke and Brandon) [15 minutes] Q&amp;amp;A and Wrap-up  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building IoT Apps: From Device to Cloud and Back Again</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/building-iot-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/building-iot-apps/</guid>
      <description>The Internet of Things is about connection. Not just connecting dumb devices to the digital world, but also connecting us in new ways to one another. Many consider IoT to be a buzzword, and yet it’s being leveraged every day to open up new business opportunities and help get people connected in homes, cities, labs, schools and a million other places, around the world.
And while getting started with IoT apps isn’t difficult, the number of concepts and moving pieces can be daunting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Get Chatty with Conversational Interface in JavaScript!</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/conversational-interface-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/conversational-interface-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Let’s build rich applications with the natural user interactions with a minimal visual interface with JavaScript with helps with natural language processing APIs! This can be Slack bots, Facebook messenger bots, or even voice-assisted browser bot using W3C web standards!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bots, IoT and AI, Oh My!</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/bots-iot-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/bots-iot-ai/</guid>
      <description>The way people interact with devices and the internet is changing quickly. We&amp;rsquo;re no longer just clicking on a desktop browser or tapping on a phone screen. We&amp;rsquo;re chatting with bots using text or voice. Or we&amp;rsquo;re interacting with all sorts of internet connected devices that, in many cases don&amp;rsquo;t even have a screen. In this free online meetup, Tomomi Imura of Slack and David Simmons of InfluxData will discuss some these important topics around chat bots, IoT and artificial intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to GraphQL &amp; Apollo</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-graphql-apollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-graphql-apollo/</guid>
      <description>GraphQL is a new buzzword today. Let’s see how to use GraphQL and Apollo in Vue to make API calls more maintainable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debunking myths: Can someone think of developers?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/debunking-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/debunking-myths/</guid>
      <description>Real life struggles. Real tips and answers. An entertaining (yes!) talk about those things we never talk about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning for Poets: The eMiLy App</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/machine-learning-for-poets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/machine-learning-for-poets/</guid>
      <description>Can an AI generate believable poetry? Join me as we romp through venerable 19th century poetry to create the eMiLy app: a new way to experience the ethereal poetry of Emily Dickinson, rooted in the 1800s but renewed for 2019. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the creation of the eMiLy app, a mobile app designed to influence the user&amp;rsquo;s mood. Feeling sad? Take a selfie, and allow Azure cognitive services to choose a happy or sad poem to alter your mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue Vixens Master Class</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/vue-vixens-master-class-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/vue-vixens-master-class-1/</guid>
      <description>In partnership with Vue Vixens, we&amp;rsquo;re offering a special event featuring two speakers from their organization covering two separate but equally important and interesting topics. Diana Rodriguez will tackle the topic of imposter syndrome - that nagging feeling that you don&amp;rsquo;t really know what you are doing that often afflicts developers (among others). Then Natalia Tepluhina will teach us about GraphQL for querying your API and Apollo, which can help convert an existing REST API into a GraphQL schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Using CodePen</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-codepen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-codepen/</guid>
      <description>CodePen is an online code editor for front end code. Let&amp;rsquo;s dig into how you use and get into some trickery you might not know about even if you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned CodePen user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes Gatsby sites so fast?</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/what-makes-gatsby-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/what-makes-gatsby-fast/</guid>
      <description>Learn what makes GatsbyJS sites so fast and hear from other developers why they like building with Gatsby. Then, watch how you can start building a highly performant site in just a few minutes. Finally, learn how to contribute to Gatsby as an open source project and get a sneak peak at upcoming feature releases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for the Modern Web Developer</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/tools-for-modern-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/tools-for-modern-dev/</guid>
      <description>Developers today have the blessing and the curse of a plethora of tools. On the one hand, we have pretty much all of our bases covered - often for free. On the other, it can be tough to keep pace with all the tools and what they are good for.
In this month&amp;rsquo;s meetup, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a couple of these tools and get to know them. First, Chris Coyier will go through CodePen and how to take advantage of this social development environment for front-end designers and developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Jamstack? Beyond static sites.</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/why-jamstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/why-jamstack/</guid>
      <description>We used to call them static sites, so why can&amp;rsquo;t we just leave that name alone? The Jamstack can actually go a lot further than delivering static sites. You can use it to deliver highly performant, secure, scalable&amp;hellip; dynamic web sites. In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll look at what the Jamstack is, and how we can use emerging tools and conventions to embrace the possibilities of modern web development without exposing ourselves to undue risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Web Development with the JAMStack</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/jamstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/jamstack/</guid>
      <description>We used to call them &amp;ldquo;static sites,&amp;rdquo; but nowadays they are anything but static. New tools, services and serverless functions are redefining the way we build &amp;ldquo;static sites&amp;rdquo; to the point that they needed a new name that represented their real capabilities: JAMStack.
In this session, Raymond Camden of Auth0 and Phil Hawksworth of Netlify will show how to get started with the JAMStack and how you can take advantage of all of these tools to build sites that are dynamic, secure and incredibly fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science in Front End Dev: It&#39;s For More than Just Interviews</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/frontend-computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/frontend-computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Watch a preview for this workshop on YouTube
A common refrain of many disillusioned front end developers is that deeper computer science concepts are useful mostly for interviews and little else. And to some extent, that can be true! However many are underestimating how often the concepts, the tradeoffs, and other associated concepts subtly arise in every day front end development.
During our time together I will present a few computer science concepts like bloom filters, tree traversals, and array sorting explain how these can show up in places you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily expect them and how you can leverage these powerful algorithms and data structures to make yourself a better programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Source Your Stuff</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/open-source-your-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/open-source-your-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Watch a preview for this workshop on YouTube
Building things so they work well in isolation, then piece them together to make the full application makes building applications easier. One thing that really helps with this kind of strategy is to open source your stuff.
In this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at an existing application, identify a good candidate component for open sourcing, and then go through the process of creating an open source project for that component and add it as a project dependency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Fundamentals for Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/functional-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/functional-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Watch a preview for this workshop on YouTube
This is a 2hr version of the popular JS Fundamentals for Functional Programming workshop. We will speed through the trickier JS fundamentals that you need to know in order to get started with improving your code style with functional programming techniques.
This is an interactive online workshop with exercises that build upon one another so it isn’t recommended to passively watch webinar style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KnowJS 2018</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/knowjs-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/knowjs-2018/</guid>
      <description>Missed KnowJS? Don&#39;t worry - all the sessions were recorded and we&#39;ve recently made them free to watch!
  KnowJS is a full-day of learning and training focused on JavaScript language fundamentals.
What makes KnowJS different?  It is hands-on training and not a conference. 100% online and interactive with live chat and Q&amp;amp;A. You also get full access to recordings to return and learn on your own schedule. We&amp;rsquo;ll feature four introductory sessions (available for free) and four hands-on sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promises, Generators, Async</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/promises-generators-async/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/promises-generators-async/</guid>
      <description>Watch a preview for this workshop on YouTube
You probably know about promises by now, but are you still writing your async code as long chains of .then()s? Did you leap for joy at the recent .finally() promise feature? Bah. That&amp;rsquo;s all anti-pattern if you ask me. Promises are one of the most powerful concepts to be added to JS, but have one of the worst API designs of any JS feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better with Failure</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/better-with-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/better-with-failure/</guid>
      <description>Remember the last time you missed a deadline at work or forgot something programmatically important to you at the time. How did you react? Our answers to failure as well as success can incrementally increase our intelligence regardless of skill. Find out why intelligence isn’t a boolean value but a direct effect of mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Success</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/developing-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/developing-success/</guid>
      <description>Knowing how to code is only one piece of being a successful developer. The other parts involve a desire to learn, an ability to communicate and work with those around you, and even, sometimes, the willingness to accept and learn from failure.
In this free event, Alyssa Nicoll of Progress and Jenell Pizarro of Skillcrush will explore how to develop some of these developer skillsets beyond coding and offer advice that will help you succeed in your career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovating is not about technology, but psychology.</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/innovating-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/innovating-technology/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is the recognition that well-read is not a destination, there is nowhere to get to and if there was somewhere to get to, you would need a thousand years to even think about getting there.&amp;rdquo; -Linda Holmes
Many people strive to be “well-read” as developers or designers, they want to know &amp;amp; do it all. But why? All in the name of being “well-read”? All just to say “Yeah — I&amp;rsquo;ve done that”?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Art-making Twitter Bot with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/twitter-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/twitter-bot/</guid>
      <description>Twitter Bots are a great interface for ingesting data and doing awesome things programmatically. In this workshop, we’ll go through how to use Python and tweepy to parse tweets targeted at our bot account. Our bot will grab the images from the tweets, and use a neural network to apply a style transfer effect that will automatically respond to the sender.
Participants can expect to leave the workshop with an understanding of how Twitter bots are architected, and boilerplate code which they can use going forward to modify for their own use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Of all the new technologies impacting developers today, machine learning has been probably the most immediately impactful. Already it is changing the way we use data to do things like predict how customers will behave or when machines may need repair. It is not an exaggeration to say that developers who understand how to leverage machine learning will become indispensable to companies in the near future.
In this free event, Paige Bailey of Microsoft and Nick Walsh of Datmo will explain the basics of machine learning and artificial intelligence - what it is and why we should care - and even walk through how to build an application based upon machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/intro-to-ai/</guid>
      <description>It feels like everyone is talking about AI these days – and what’s worse, everyone seems to have a different term for it! “Deep Learning”, “Machine Learning”, “Artificial Intelligence”: what do they all mean, really? Are the concerns about ethical algorithms and automation of jobs grounded in fact, or are they overhyped? And what language will SkyNet be implemented in? (My money’s on JavaScript.)
In this session we’ll answer those questions – and walk through what machine learning really is: how to build a model by ingesting data, training on it, testing, and then deploying to production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Your Apps - Performance and Debugging</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/improving-your-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/improving-your-apps/</guid>
      <description>Most experienced developers will tell you that hardest parts of the job comes after the initial code is written - when it is time to refine, tune and test the application. It can take a deep understanding of the languages, tools and code to maximize the applications performance and experience.
In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a deeper look at some ways that you can improve your application development - from a deep dive into CSS internals to more general trends and performance issues that can impact your applications user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not Dark Magic - Pulling Back the Curtains From Your Stylesheets</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/its-not-dark-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/its-not-dark-magic/</guid>
      <description>All too often developers are left completely puzzled when the browser renders CSS in ways they didn’t expect. It’s not dark magic though and as developers, we know that computers are just parsing our instructions. While many talks discuss how to fix common bugs, this talk will focus on the why by taking a deep dive into browser internals to see how our styles are parsed and rendered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hunt for the Unicorn Performance Metric</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/unicorn-performance-metric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/unicorn-performance-metric/</guid>
      <description>Slow websites suck. We know that intuitively. But how do we define &amp;ldquo;slow&amp;rdquo;? And how do we define &amp;ldquo;suck&amp;rdquo;? These are ephemeral words, yet as developers, designers, UX pros, and performance engineers, we&amp;rsquo;re tasked with quantifying them, and then moving on to the next step of figuring out how fast is fast enough for our users.
The key to a good user experience is quickly delivering the content your visitors care about the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop a Messenger Bot in Pure Ruby</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/ruby-messenger-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/ruby-messenger-bot/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to quickly get started with Rubotnik boilerplate to build a bot with rich features. Rubotnik is framework- and database agnostic and promotes a «bot-end» approach to build conversational interfaces with an easy-to-follow DSL. And it’s easily deployable to Heroku!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Severless on Easy Mode</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-easy-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-easy-mode/</guid>
      <description>With functions as a service, cloud providers have signaled the smallest billable unit of computation is a single function execution. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautifully simple idea, rejecting the metaphor of a server, and freeing developers to design smaller and simpler services. We can iterate on our code with a high degree of isolation, without fear of affecting other parts of the system; deploy systems in seconds with zero downtime; and always be available regardless of load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Development</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/future-of-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/future-of-development/</guid>
      <description>Technology is moving quickly - things like bots, serverless, VR/AR, IoT and more are quickly changing both how we develop and what we develop for. And we thought things got complex when we were just targeting desktop and mobile devices! In this free, online event we&amp;rsquo;ll cover two of those trends that are shaping how we develop and what we develop for.
As we discussed in October, the trend towards serverless architectures is changing the way developers build their apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh No You Didn’t: Conflict Management in Today’s Tech Industry</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/conflict-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/conflict-management/</guid>
      <description>On some level, conflict is an unavoidable part of any workplace - it’s tough enough for groups of people to always get along, even when the stresses of work aren’t involved. But how we choose to handle that conflict can factor hugely in the success of the team and in our own happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh No You Didn’t: Conflict Management Panel</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/oh-no-you-didnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/oh-no-you-didnt/</guid>
      <description>In this interactive event, our panel will discuss conflict that they have personally faced and how they handled it (even if not always perfectly or even well). We’ll invite the audience to chime in via chat with their questions or to share situations that they are facing/have faced. In the end, we hope that everyone will leave with new techniques that we use to resolve our conflicts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Serverless</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/going-serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/going-serverless/</guid>
      <description>Lately the term serverless is everywhere, which naturally makes developers skeptical that it is a marketing buzzword. However, behind the term is a useful concept of tools and architecture that takes the need to worry about servers (if not actual servers themselves) out of the equation. In this free online event, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore what serverless is, why it is an important new development, and where it will have the most impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Provider Serverless Apps using The Serverless Framework</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-framework/</guid>
      <description>Serverless Framework has recently introduced support for multiple serverless providers. You can now deploy serverless applications to OpenWhisk, Google Cloud Functions and Azure Functions as well as AWS Lambda. This allows you to develop platform-independent serverless applications. James Thomas has been working on the OpenWhisk implementation. In this talk, he will introduce the new feature, show you how to run serverless applications on different providers and explain the challenges in developing platform-agnostic serverless apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless JavaScript OMG</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/serverless-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Serverless is the new buzzword; which is what we needed - another buzzword. Serverless refers to new technologies that let us, as developers, reframe the way we think about building applications when we don’t have to think about the “server” part. Serverless doesn’t mean “no server”; it just means you don’t have to worry about that piece of your application anymore, and we’ll take a look at why that is a beautiful thing for JavaScript developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring JavaScript Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/exploring-javascript-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/exploring-javascript-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>It seems that there are few guarantees in life, but two of them are that the sun will rise in the morning and, with it, will come at least two new JavaScript frameworks. So how is a developer supposed to keep up? How can you tell the contenders from the pretenders? In this free online event, Jen Looper and Holly Schinsky will take a look at some of the more prominent new frameworks to help you decide if they are worth exploring further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preact - Up and Running</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/preact-up-and-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/preact-up-and-running/</guid>
      <description>Yep, you heard it right, not React, but Preact! Let’s take a look at this small, fast, lightweight JavaScript library that gives you great performance in a small package - about 3.5 kb! Touting itself as ‘closer to the metal’, Preact targets modern browsers to deliver a fast, modern web experience. Let’s dive into Preact, learning how it differs from React and how easy it is to build a web presence with this small, but effective, tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Point of Vue</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/point-of-vue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/point-of-vue/</guid>
      <description>In this session you will be introduced to Vue.js, a popular Javascript framework with over 63k stars on GitHub since released in 2014. This introduction will include an examination of how Vue compares to other popular frameworks, an overview of the syntax, supported tooling and libraries to be aware of, and some useful resources to help you get started developing your own apps with Vue.
Resources
 slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Bits and Bytes to Atoms</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/from-bits-and-bytes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/from-bits-and-bytes/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s never been a better time to tinker with electronics. Once the domain of hard core enthusiasts with a penchant for obsessing over optimizing C code, the world of electronics and the IoT is now flush with boards, kits and devices that are tailor-made for the new maker, and which have all the speed and power that the pros have. If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, you already know half of what you need in order to start lighting things up and making things go, and there are a number of kits out there that let you use the languages you know to power the IoT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/iot-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/iot-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>For many developers, hardware can be intimidating. This is why the Internet of Things can seem simultaneously appealing and scary. There are so many promising ideas on how to mix code and devices, but how do all the wires and devices connect? Is there soldering involved?
In this event, Brandon Satrom and Brad Marsh will show simple and practical ways for getting started in IoT - from basic electronics to smart home integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Smart Home Fun</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/making-smart-home-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/making-smart-home-fun/</guid>
      <description>With cheaper and more configurable IOT platforms now available, many of us have made our homes more efficient and more intelligent. Now it’s time to make them more fun. In this session we’ll explore easy ways that you can introduce new and exciting experiences into your home using your existing setup. We’ll show that with a few cheap parts, some code and an Arduino or two, the magic of your Disney World vacation can be recreated in your living room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing in JavaScript in 2017</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/events/javascript-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/events/javascript-2017/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript development has seen a lot of changes in recent years, between new specifications like ES6 and ES7 to new tooling like TypeScript. This free event takes a look at some of these advancements and how developers can realistically start taking advantage of them today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ES6, ES7, where do I start???</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/es6-es7-where-to-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/es6-es7-where-to-start/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript has evolved rapidly over the past few years and while that is, 100%, a good thing, some developers may be feeling a bit behind. In this session, Raymond will spend some time talking about how JS has changed, and is changing, and what are some good practical ways to start making use of modern JavaScript in your code right now.
Download the slide deck here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Was Wrong About TypeScript</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/sessions/wrong-about-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/sessions/wrong-about-typescript/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I made a strong argument that TypeScript was destined to be irrelevant and that my company should not use it in any of our projects. I was wrong. In 2017, TypeScript is taking over the JavaScript world, and we now use TypeScript for pretty much everything we build.
In this talk we’ll talk a look at why TypeScript succeeded where other compile-to-JavaScript frameworks like CoffeeScript and Dart have languished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>https://cfe.dev/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 18:52:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cfe.dev/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Us Have a questions? A suggestion for a virtual meetup topic? Or are you interested in speaking or sponsorship? Feel free to reach out!
 Don’t fill this out:  Name  Email  Message   Send     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>